<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
  ~ Copyright (C) 2019 The Android Open Source Project
  ~
  ~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  ~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  ~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  ~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  ~ limitations under the License.
  -->
<tutorialBundle
    name="What's New"
    resourceRoot="/"
    stepByStep="false"
    hideStepIndex="true"
    version="2021.1.1.2">
  <feature
      name="What's New in Bumblebee">
    <tutorial
        key="whats-new"
        label=" What's New in Bumblebee"
        icon="stable/whats_new_icon.png"
        remoteLink="https://developer.android.com/studio/releases#bumblebee"
        remoteLinkLabel="Read in a browser">
      <description>
        <![CDATA[
          This panel describes some of the new features and behavior changes
          included in this update.
          <br><br>
          To open this panel again later, select <b>Help &gt; What's New in Android Studio</b>
          from the main menu.
          ]]>
      </description>
      <step label="Unified Gradle test runner">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
              <center><img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/2021.1.1/consolidated-test-runner-428.png"
                 width="428"
                 alt="Gradle instrumented test runner in Android Studio" />
              </center>
              <br>
              <p>
              Depending on whether you run your tests from Android Studio or from the command line
              using the Android Gradle plugin, such as on your continuous integration server, you
              might see different test results, such as tests passing using one runner and failing
              on another. That's because each implements a different version of the Android
              instrumented test runner.
            </p>
              <br />
            <p>
              To resolve this issue, Android Studio Bumblebee now also uses Gradle’s Android
              instrumented test runner when running your tests. So, you should expect consistent
              when running tests locally. This is a similar change to Android Studio Arctic Fox,
              which introduced all unit tests to run through Gradle.
            </p>
              <br>
              <a href="https://d.android.com/io-21/android-testing">Learn more</a>
              <br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="New in Layout Inspector">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
              <p>
                <b>Capture layout hierarchy snapshots</b><br>
                Layout Inspector now allows you to save snapshots of your running app’s layout
                hierarchy, so that you can easily share them with others or refer to them later.
                Snapshots capture the data you would typically see when using the Layout Inspector,
                including a detailed 3D rendering of your layout, the component tree of your View,
                Compose, or hybrid layout, and detailed attributes for each component of your UI.
                When you want to capture a snapshot, click <b>Export snapshot<b> from the Layout
                Inspector toolbar.
              </p>
              <p>
                <b>Capture layout hierarchy snapshots</b><br>
                In Android Studio Bumblebee, you can now use the Layout Inspector to inspect semantic
                information in your Compose layouts. When selecting a Compose node, use the Attributes
                window to check whether it declares semantic information directly, merges semantics
                from its children, or both. To quickly identify which nodes include semantics, either
                declared or merged, use select the View options dropdown in the Component Tree window
                and select Highlight Semantics Layers.
              </p>
              <br>
              <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/releases#new-in-layout-inspector">Learn more</a>
              <br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="New Device Manager">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
              <center><img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/2021.1.1/new-device-manager-wna.png"
                 width="428"
                 alt="New device manager" />
              </center>
              <br>
              <p>
                The Device Manager is a stand-in replacement for the AVD Manager, both from Android
                Studio’s Welcome Screen or after you open a project. The Device Manager introduces
                some new capabilities that make this feature more easy to create and manage all of
                your local test devices, such as a flexible tool window, separate tabs to manage your
                virtual and physical devices, and details of each connected device.
            </p>
            <p>
              Open the Device Manager by selecting <b>More Actions &gt; Virtual Device Manager</b>
              from the Welcome screen, select <b>View &gt; Tool Windows &gt; Device Manager</b> after
              opening a project.
            </p>
              <br>
              <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/releases#new-device-manager">Learn more</a>
              <br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="New in App Inspection">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
              <p>
                <b>Inspect Jobs, Alarms, and Wakelocks</b><br>
                The Background Task Inspector now allows you to inspect your app’s Jobs, Alarms, and
                Wakelocks, in addition to the existing support for inspecting Workers. Each type of
                asynchronous task now appears under the appropriate heading in the inspector tab,
                allowing you to easily monitor its status and progress. Similar to Workers, you can
                select a Job, Alarm, or Wakelock to inspect its detailed information in the Task
                Details panel.
            </p>
            <p>
              <b>Network Inspector</b><br>
              The Network Profiler in the Profilers tool window has now moved to the App Inspection
              tool window. If you’ve previously used the Network Profiler, all the same features and
              rich network traffic data is still available. Simply deploy your app to a device
              running API level 26 and higher and open the App Inspector > Network Inspector tab.
            </p>
              <br>
              <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/releases#new_in_app_inspection">Learn more</a>
              <br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Emulator runs inside Studio by default">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>
            The Android Emulator now runs directly inside Android Studio by default.
            This helps conserve screen real estate, and gives you the ability to write and
            test your apps without leaving Android Studio.
            </p><br/>
            <p>
            When the emulator is running, you'll have access to common emulator actions like device rotation
            and extended control options like navigation playback.
            </p><br/>
            <p>
            To run the emulator in a separate window instead go to <b> File&nbsp;> Settings&nbsp;> Tools&nbsp;> Emulator </b> and
            deselect <i>Launch in a tool window</i>.
            </p>
              <br>
              <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/releases#android_emulator_now_runs_directly_inside_android_studio_by_default">Learn more</a>
              <br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
        <stepElement>
          <action
              key="android.emulator.open.settings"
              label="Open Emulator Settings">
          </action>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Wireless debugging">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>
            Android Studio now supports the wireless debugging feature in Android 11 and higher devices.
            Pair and deploy your app from Android Studio over Wi-Fi without using a USB Cable or managing
            ADB connections via the command line.
            </p>
              <br>
              <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/releases#wireless-debugging">Learn more</a>
              <br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Compose interactive preview">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>
            The interactive preview feature is now enabled by default. The interactive preview allows you to interact
            with a preview as it would work on a device. The interactive preview is isolated in a sandbox environment,
            where you can click elements and enter user input in the preview.
            </p>
              <br>
              <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/releases#interactive-preview">Learn more</a>
              <br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Animated Vector Drawable (AVD) preview">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>
            The Animated Drawable Preview tool offers the ability to preview the animated drawable resources.
            This tool helps developers preview &lt;animation-list&gt;, &lt;animated-vector&gt;, and &lt;animated-selector&gt;
            resources in Android Studio instantly.
            </p>
              <br>
              <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/releases#avd-preview">Learn more</a>
              <br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <footerStep label="">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
              <br><em>Last updated 1/25/2022</em><br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </footerStep>
    </tutorial>
  </feature>
</tutorialBundle>
